{
    "id": "fb84dbbd6d9c449899511f2ed97efca3",
    "title": "Do vs. Does vs. Did | Grammar Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "6883192afbbf4f62a4ec0d3ea82bce7d",
            "title": "Do vs. Does vs. Did",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Whom ………………………. you want to meet?",
                    "description": "Use do with you. As there is no reference to past time, use the simple present here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "do",
                        "does",
                        "did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "What ……………………… you do then?",
                    "description": "Then shows distance in time. Hence, use the past tense here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "do",
                        "does",
                        "did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Sam ……………………… not have a good job.",
                    "description": "Use does with a singular subject. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "do",
                        "does",
                        "did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Leena ……………………….. not want to quit her job.",
                    "description": "Did is also possible here however, since there is no reference to past time, use the simple present. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "does",
                        "do",
                        "did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "How ……………………….. you know him?",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "did",
                        "do",
                        "does"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "How ………………………. they react when they heard the news?",
                    "description": "Here the subordinate clause is in the past tense hence, we use a past tense here as well. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "do",
                        "does",
                        "did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………………. you understand the consequences of your action?",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Do",
                        "Does",
                        "Did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Smoking …………………………. cause cancer.",
                    "description": "Use does with singular subjects. Does smoke means the same as smokes. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "do",
                        "does",
                        "did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "That ………………………… not seem plausible.",
                    "description": "That is a singular subject hence, we use does with it. Did is also possible here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "do",
                        "does",
                        "did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………….. you meet him yesterday?",
                    "description": "Yesterday is a past time adverb hence, we use did here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Do",
                        "Does",
                        "Did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "At first she ………………………….. not recognize him.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "do",
                        "does",
                        "did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "My parents ………………………… not support my desire to become an actor.",
                    "description": "Either do not or did not is possible here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "do",
                        "does",
                        "did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}